我说Bubs 咱总该有个规矩吧 不然的话一切都乱套了
No, Bubs. I mean, there's gotta be rules, or else things get fucked up.
对瘾君子没啥规矩可讲的
Ain't no rules with dope fiends.
警察把你逮着的时候 你就得做点什么
When the police got you shackled up, you make a move, right?
你为了帮自己脱身 你会不为任何理由地告密
You help yourself out. But you just start snitching for no reason.
- 那可没-- - 打住 打住!
- that doesn't make no... - Whoa, whoa!
让我跟进一下你的想法
Let me track this.
你是说假如你被警察抓起来你就可以告密
You hypopulating that you can tattletale when you locked up...
但你却不能直接为了钱而这样做?
but you can't do it straight up for the money?
我不想打击你 小子 但你的想法也太不靠谱了
I mean, no offense, son, but that's some weak-ass thinking.
模棱两可藏头缩尾的 整个儿一窝囊废
You equivocating like a motherfuck.
那好 告密人就是告密人 行了吧?
Okay, so a snitch is a snitch, right?
- 这就对了 - 那为什么要当告密得?
- There you go. - So why be one, man?
我们就做点不法的事儿混得还行 何必--
I mean, we're getting by with our capers.
我们每天他妈的在这儿偷东西乱窜
We getting by out here every damn day ripping and running...
什么能显摆的屁也没有
and ain't got shit to show for it.
这不是小卒生涯的一部分嘛
It's part of being a soldier.
你不就这样的人嘛 你就是这么说的
I mean, that's you, right, that's what you says.
是啊 这就是为什么我不开车 而是用脚来跑所有的路
Yeah, that's why I put all this mileage on these feet.
你就等着吧 等到你不再是傻小子的那天吧
You wait. You wait till you ain't a pup no more.
看你到时会不会想着 为自己找些更稳当的事来做
See if you ain't looking for something a little more steady for your own self.
搞什么鬼? 你这么快就焉了?
What the fuck? You ill already?
这一大早还没过呢
It's not even past morning.
我没事 我好着呢 我好着呢
I'm cool, man. I'm fine, I'm fine.
我说 咱去跟我那Kima姐们儿接上头 等咱拿到钱 你就会好起来了
Look, we hook up with my girl Kima, we get paid, you gonna be better.
去你的 Bubs 我他妈可不告密
Fuck that, Bubs, all right? I'm not a fucking snitch.
你知道我跟你完全不是一个想法
You know I could argue the other side.
假如说扔个硬币就能决定你免于起诉 那你就是个告密的
Say that if you drop dime to duck a charge, then you a snitch.
你干这个营生 你就是个专业人士
You do it as a living, you a professional.
停下 停下 停下 你看到那边那架梯子没?
Hold up, hold up, hold up. You see that ladder right there?
就像从前一样 伙计
Just like old times, man.
我做坏人 你做大侠
I'll be the bad guy, you be the Lone Ranger.
别搞那个人啦 去找我那姐们儿能赚更多钱
Leave that man be. We get paid more hooking up to my girl.
这可明摆着的现成钞票啊
But that's cash money right there.
那是个白人 最好还是由我来做坏人 省得把他给搞糊涂了
With the white man, I best be the bad guy. That way he ain't confused.
行啊 我们在巷子里会合
All right, meet me in the alley.
见鬼
Fuck.
- 哎 先生 - 哎
- Yo, mister. - Yo.
把你钱包扔下来 不然我这就把梯子拉倒
Throw down your wallet, or I'm gonna jerk this ladder right out.
- 什么? 不 不要啊 - 我穷人一个 说到做到
- What? No, no. - I'm a poor man who ain't playing.
- 不要 求你了 救命! - 把钱他妈的扔下来
- No, please. Help! - Throw down the goddamn money.
- 好的 - 哎 离那人远点儿
- Okay. - Hey! Hey! Leave that man alone.
谢谢你
Oh, thank you.
刚才太吓人了
It's crazy, man.
那家伙搞什么啊? 见鬼
- What's that guy doing? - Shit.
- 来 给 - 不 不 这我不能拿
- Here, here. - I can't, I can't, I can't.
别介 你救了我
No, you saved my ass.
这是点小意思 算我谢你的
It's appreciated, you know.
Bubs 你丫绝对想不到
Yo, Bubs, you won't fucking believe this.
Bubs
Bubs...
火线重案组 第三季 第五集 金盆洗手
The Wire S03E05 Straight and True
* When you walk through the garden *
* You gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* He's gonna save your soul *
* You gotta keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* He's got the fire and the fury *
* At his command *
* Well you don't have to worry *
* If you hold on to Jesus hand *
* We'll all be safe from Satan *
* When the thunder rolls *
* Just gotta help me keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* You gotta help me keep the devil *
"我本来还对咱们怀着期望呢"  ---McNulty
Dennis 你起床没? Dennis!
Dennis, you up? Dennis!
唉 早啊
Mee-maw, hey.
看来你今天不用工作啊
Guess you're not working today, huh?
我现在上的是夜班
I'm working nights now.
在酒吧 守门口的
At a bar. Working the door.
你知道 就是...
You know, it's just...
就是暂时先做着 等我找份好点的工作再说
Just till I find something a little bit better.
是吗
Yeah, huh?
我想起来了
Reminds me.
咱们的朋友今早又打电话来
Your friend called again this morning.
她说是让你记得你的预约
She said for you to remember your appointment.
说那里有份工作 如果你还想找的话
Says there's a job in it, if you still looking.
你说的是Marlo 对吧?
So Marlo, right?
他有个马仔护着他 名字叫Chris Partlow
He got this one boy watching his back, name be Chris Partlow.
Bartlow 是不是"巴"字打头?
Bartlow with a "B"?
前半截是"耙" 就是白人梳那种耙分头
"Part," like white people got in their hair.
后半截是"篓" 就像是说瘾君子的屁股篓
And "low," like a low-bottom dope fiend.
- 耙篓 - 对了 是这么念的
- Partlow. - Yeah, what I said.
他是Marlo的打手
So he's Marlo's muscle.
他们说...
They say...
- 这信息值多少钱? - 5块 我看能不能搞到带他照片的身份证明
- How much is that worth? - $5, if I can work up a photo ID.
这是Fruit那小子用过的
The boy, Fruit, he used that.
- 是那个控制着Marlo其中一个街角的Fruit? - 小心点 上面有指纹
- Fruit who runs one of Marlo's corners? - Careful, it's got prints.
指纹哈?  瞧你 还给我来罪案鉴证科那套鬼话呢
Prints, huh? Look at you... getting all CSI on me and shit.
带指纹的东西准能派得上用场 这该值点钱了吧?
Now, a burner with prints, that's gotta mean cash money, right?
如果我能提取出指纹 证明是Fruit本人的 我可以给你10块
If I could pull a print, get Fruit ID'd, I can go to $10.
如果我带你去Marlo藏他的奔驰车的地方 你又给多少呢?
And if I show you where Marlo hides his Mercedes?
奔驰能值15块
Benz would go for $15.
我说你太不了解我的处境了 我这可是在老虎嘴里拔牙啊
I mean, you don't know it, but these are hard times in a hard land.
你还不如杀了我得了 姐们儿
You killing me out here, girl.
好吧 奔驰给25块
All right. $25 for the Benz.
你们真是大好人
You good peoples.
那这些加起来 总共40块钱对吧?
So let's total up. We at $40, right?
- 给 这些你帮我存着 - 存着? 为什么?
- Here, bank that for me. - Bank it? For what?
我有个计划 姐们儿
Got me a plan, girl.
外头那些小子们  他们身上都穿那种大白T恤
The hoppers out here, they only be wearing them big, white T-shirts...
不过没穿几次就扔了
a couple of times before they chuck them.
所以我就想着 一边在这儿为你们做事
So I'm thinking, while I'm out here working for y'all,
一边也别闲着 到街角去卖T恤给他们
I get my ends up...sell them shirts on the corner.
我就会有赚不完的花花银子了
I'll make my nut coming and going.
B&B企业 豪华公寓单元发展商 最低300元起
说真的 我觉得你已经功夫做到家了
Truthfully, I don't know what more you could have done.
Charlie说得对 头儿 你尽力了
Charlie's right, boss. You tried.
是那些该死的混混们不合作
Fucking hoodleheads won't cooperate.
你让他们拥有一两块自己的地盘
Here you are giving them their own block or two...
提供地方让他们卖毒品 可他们他妈的有听话么?
offering them a place to sell drugs in peace, and do they even fucking listen?
更可恶的是 如果这方法能实施起来
It's a damn shame, too, 'cause if it worked...
你可能已经对社区起到了积极的影响
you might have had a positive effect on the community.
当班负责人 请电前台
Shift commander, call the front desk.
你们这班人都是满脑子的大粪
You guys are some lying sacks of shit.
- 我是说 长官 - 我想
- I'm saying, sir... - I'm guessing...
你大概对我们应该从哪儿开始着手有一些想法吧
that you have some thoughts on where we should go from here.
这个嘛 长官 我们想采取一种 改良过的斑马线式操作
Well, sir, we were thinking a modified zebra operation.
在区与区之间轮流跨接行动  结合决不手软的行动宗旨
Jump-outs rotating from sector to sector, combined with a zero-tolerance approach.
我们从每一更班具体指定两个人 成立一个机动小组
We detail a couple of men from each shift, build a flex unit...
加强抓捕和扫荡卖毒点的力度
double up on the head-knocking and corner-clearing.
也就是说做更多跟现在一样的工作
More of the same, you mean.
- 但更好些 - 更好?
- But better. - Better?
总比什么都不做要好
Better than nothing.
实在是受不了这些鬼玩意儿了
Fuck this bullshit already.
伙计 他们给我们15箱合法票券
Man, they gave us 15 cases of legal...
可里面的印花债券数量却少了
but they shorted us on the colored bonds.
这是怎么一回事?
What's going on there?
我来招呼这人
I got this.
- 警官 - 是警探 String
- Officer. - Detective, String.
你记得Bird那单初审案子吧 我是当时负责的警探McNulty
You remember. Bird trial. Detective McNulty.
您要复印些什么文件吗?
You want something copied, man?
搜查令或者是法庭令?
Search warrant, court papers?
有什么我能帮得上忙的 出句声就行了
Anything I can do to help, you know.
我怎么没见你在道上混呢
I ain't seen you around the way.
我已经没在外面混了 你要找我的话 来这儿就好
I'm not around the way no more. You wanna find me, I'm right here.
来这儿哈?
Right here, huh?
这家店还有些其他的地产生意 我现在做的就这些
This and some real estate I'm working on is all.
你知道 这都让我忙不过来了 真的
You know, more than enough to occupy me, really.
这说起来 你在哪儿住呢 老兄?
Say, where you living, man?
我在哪儿住?
Where am I living?
如果你想着住到城里来
Well, if you thinking of coming downtown...
我手头有些公寓八个月后就上市了
I got some condos about to come on the line in eight months.
你说句话  我可以在歌剧院旁边给您留一套好的
You say the word, I'm gonna hook you up something nice down there by the Hippodrome.
复式套间 非常不错哦
Loft apartments. Real nice.
你真让我失望 String 我本来还对咱们怀着期望呢
You disappoint me, String. I had such fucking hopes for us.
您走好 警官
Have a nice day, Officer.
你看到这篇东西没?
You see this shit?
记得前两个月在Clifton湖停车场 被开枪打死的那个小孩么?
Remember that kid who got shot in the parking lot in Lake Clifton a couple months back?
因为毒品纠纷对吧? 怎么啦?
Drug feud, right? What about it?
昨天晚上 在胡同里 他们发现那个唯一的目击证人
Well, last night, they just found the only eyewitness...in an alleyway,
全身都是窟窿
bunch of holes in him.
接着呢?
And?
什么叫接着呢?
What do you mean, "And?"
咱这可是在说一名给州里做证的证人
You're talking about a state's witness.
一名这么高曝光率的案件的证人给杀了
You let a witness get killed in a high-profile case like this,
这不明摆着告诉人家 这个城市已经烂得没法治了嘛
it says "The city's broke and can't be fixed."
- 听上去像是我们找到了一个症结 - 不 暂时先不要管他妈的政治
- Sounds like we found an issue. - No, fuck the politics for a minute.
你知道 这是那种我们大家 应该站在同一立场处理的事情
You know, this is something we all need to be on the same page with.
我是在说真的 Tony
I'm serious, Tony.
如果咱们对这种事情置之不理 要不了多久咱们就什么都没有了
You let shit like this stand, pretty soon you got nothing left.
你想要大肆宣扬 然后用来打击市长?
You gonna go public and bang the Mayor with it?
还是说你想要打击Burrell和州检察官?
You gonna bang Burrell and the state's attorney then?
我没打算打击任何人
I ain't gonna bang nobody.
我不是说了嘛 咱不扯上政治 仅此一次
Like I said, fuck the politics for once.
但这儿确实是有个问题 我要想办法来解决掉它
But there is a problem here, and I'm gonna do something to fix it.
你要去取你的超人披风和小红裤衩了么
You want your cape and the little red underpants...
还是你把那些玩意儿都藏在电话亭里了?
or you stash that shit in the phone booth?
我总在琢磨这事呢
I always wondered about that.
伙计 要是能给我来一件那样的就好了
Man, I'd like a piece of that.
你什么样的女人都想来一件
You'd like any piece at all.
死黑鬼 我想要一件你妈
Nigga, I'd like a piece of your mother.
丫的 少给我惹事生非
Yo, stop fucking around.
又不是我开的头
I ain't started that shit.
妈的 看她让咱那小弟兴奋得都鼻孔朝天了
Yo, now she got our boy with his nose wide open.
他从咱这儿偷东西 看样子多数是为了她
He's stealing from us, and she most likely the reason for it.
你们盯着那个女的 用不了多久她就会带我们找到钱了
Y'all stay with the girl. She'll soon enough show us the money.
你上哪去?
Hey, where you going?
我有我的事要做
Yo, I got something I got to do.
你应该跟我们一起呆着查这档子事儿的
You supposed to be here on this shit with us.
你们俩吊着那个女的 我会回来在前面跟你们会合
Y'all stay with the girl. I'll get back with y'all down the way.
你说啥?
Say what?
我之前定了个约会 得要守约
Yo, I made a date a while back... got to keep.
哥定了个约会 得要守约
Man made a date, got to keep.
我看哪 他肯定是跟那个小王八蛋一样在泡妞吧
Hey, we find out he pussy-whipped like this motherfucker over here.
再一次 从数据来看
Now, once again, from the data...
最多车子被盗是什么时间?
when are most cars stolen?
回长官 是在晚上
Sir, at night.
你的小队 我相信  是负责制止机动车盗窃的
And your unit, which I believe...is charged with deterring the theft of autos...
你们什么时间工作?
when do you work?
日班 8点到4点
The day shift, 8:00 to 4:00.
但是长官 我想解释一下...
But, sir, as I tried to explain...
你的职责很明确
Your position is clear.
你们在白天比晚上逮捕了更多的偷车贼
You effect more arrests of car thieves during the daylight than at night.
你看 我们的耳朵很管用 你说的我们都听到了
You see, our ears work. We heard you.
但现在问题来了 为什么你他妈的没听到我们说什么?
But the question becomes, why the fuck can't you hear us?
- 长官 我不... - 局长先生打算要把这个部门
- Sir, I don't... - The Commissioner is attempting to move this department
从暗黑时代带入21世纪
from the Dark Ages into the 21st century.
就是说依靠电脑生成数据来防止罪案发生
That means preventing crime by relying on computer-generated data...
而不是靠你他妈的糊涂混帐狗屁直觉
not on your fly-by-your-fucked-up-ass instinct.
星期五晚把市中心停车场盗车贼数字给我
Give me the auto-theft numbers for downtown parking lots on Friday nights.
长官 我得去查一下
Sir, I have to check that.
找枪的事进展到哪了?
Where are we with the gun?
总警监 我之前已经说得很清楚
Colonel, I was made to understand...
找回Dozerman警员丢失的武器 是头等重要的事情
that recovering Officer Dozerman's lost weapon was a priority.
枪 是的 我们在找 长官 说话这会儿就有进展了
The gun, yes, we're on it, sir. Making progress as we speak.
队长?
Lieutenant?
长官 我现在明白我们要防患于未然
Sir, I now understand that prevention is the way to go...
我们会立即配合电脑数据更改我们的时间
and we'll immediately change our hours to reflect the data.
好吧 警督
All right, Lieutenant.
屁话连篇
Fecal gravity.
只要找对了人 一打他屁股就准能出屎
You beat on the right people and the shit rolls down the hill.
- 你是叫Dennis么? - 叫我Cutty就好
- Dennis, is it? - Cutty works for me.
那我就叫你Cutty
Cutty then.
就我们俩么?
So it's just gonna be us here?
你知道 我是说 Grace
You know, I mean, Grace...
Grace修女以你的名义叫我们来 不过以我所知她并没打算到场
Sister Grace called on your behalf but to my knowledge, she didn't plan to be here.
她是个美丽的女人
She's a beautiful woman.
一个男人应该对这样一个女人 说些言不由衷的话来接近她
A man might say things he didn't mean to stand closer to a woman like that.
我听说你现在在找工作
You're in the job market though, I understand.
有几个问题
A couple of questions.
你有高中文凭或者高中水平证书么?
You got a high-school diploma, GED?
有任何工作经验没?
Any work experience?
我曾经在一仓库做过几个月 那是86年的事了
I worked in a warehouse for a couple of months back in, like, '86.
你希望教会能怎么帮你呢?
How do you see the church helping you?
也许能给我找个工作或者 把我放在什么候选名单上之类的
Maybe get me some jobs or put my name on a list or something. I don't know.
我得先告诉你 我们的做法不是这样的
I should tell you up front, we don't do like that here.
你想要一份工作 你要做点什么去争取
You want a job, you're gonna have to work to get it.
我们会提供帮助 但你是那个付出努力的人
We'll help, but it's gonna be your sweat.
话又说回来 首先你要去上 考高中水平证书的学习班
With that said, then, the first thing is to get you enrolled in a GED program.
你看 我不想让你失望
Look, I don't mean to put you out,
但这 这跟我所想的完全不是一回事
but this...This ain't how I thought it was gonna play.
我 Oscar 还有别的一大帮人 我们眼睁睁看着
Me, Oscar, a bunch of the guys...we seen it.
一点忙也帮不上
Couldn't help it.
他们基本上就从我们旁边跑过
They practically ran right past us.
那个受害人 就是那个女孩 拿着把枪的
And the victim, the girl, had a gun.
她是属于哪一伙的?
Whose side was she on?
搞不清楚 他们动作太快了
Couldn't tell. They weren't doing slow motion.
有没有哪个人有一条大伤疤的?
Did any of them have a big scar?
要是见到他们中的任何一个人 你能再认出他们来么?
Do you think you'd be able to recognize any of them again if you saw them?
- 只能认出Omar - 这么说你认识Omar?
- Just Omar. - So you know Omar?
Omar常到这块儿来转悠
Omar came up around here.
好啊 Bruiser 这非常好
That's good, Bruiser, very good.
你当然知道Omar有条伤疤 对吧?
You do know Omar has a scar, right?
他有么?
He do?
我们还是去我办公室 把你说的都写下来
I think we better go to my office, put this down on paper.
来吧
Come on.
警员 打扰了 警员
Officer. Excuse me, Officer.
这里是North街跟Pulaski街交界处么?
Is this North and Pulaski?
我敢肯定Dozerman是在 North街跟Pulaski街交界处被枪打中的
'Cause I could fucking swear Dozerman was shot up at North and Pulaski.
喔 不对 等一下 让我猜一猜
No, no, wait, wait, let me guess.
为了找到你那警员同事的配枪 你于是找上了这位好公民
The pursuit of your fellow officer's service weapon has led you to this fine citizen.
告诉我 好心的先生 你知道那位警员的武器大概在哪儿么?
Tell me, kind sir, do you know the whereabouts of said officer's weapon?
我看你是不知道
I didn't think so.
拘留中心来电话了
Calls from the detention center.
看来里头有些善良的灵魂在哭求着 为你那濒临绝望的调查工作提供帮助
Some kind souls begging to assist you in your foundering investigation.
我得先做点陪审团的工作 把这人的口供记下来再说
Let me just grand-jury my man here, lock in his story.
现在先去找枪 回头再录他的口供
Now for the gun. Later for his story.
这是你们警司的命令
And that's your sergeant talking.
哥们儿 擦擦干净你的鼻子
Yo, wipe your nose, yo.
搞什么啊? 见鬼
What the fuck? Oh, shit.
王八蛋 你这么个出现法差点没吓死我们
Motherfucker, you scared the shit out of us coming up like that.
这玩意儿确实能让你变得疑神疑鬼的 哥们儿
This shit do make you paranoid, yo.
别客气 黑鬼 享用点这玩意儿吧
Go on, nigga, hit this shit.
不了 我明天还要做尿检呢
No, man, I gotta drop urine tomorrow.
哎呦 你担心那个?
Yo, you worried about that?
没事儿 黑鬼 我们帮你搞定
Go ahead, nigga. We got that covered.
这种事你也能搞定?
Oh, you got that covered?
怎么着 你以为只有你一个鸟人在假释啊?
What, you think you're the only motherfucker on parole?
- 你丫的 把那玩意儿给我 - 这就对了嘛
- Yo, nigga, give me that shit. - There you go.
说说看 她这一天怎么过的?
All right. What was her day?
她叫辆出租去了Towson镇购物中心
She caught a hack up to Towson Town Mall.
进了两家珠宝店 都分别买了东西出来
Hit two jewelry stores and came back with bags from both.
到她跟那男的再见面时
By the time she caught up with our boy...
她脖子就挂着从其中一家店里买的项链
she was wearing one of them shits around her neck.
把另外一条链子给了他
Gave the other one to him.
就好象他的钱就是她的一样
You know, his and hers, like.
是的 Cutty 她跟这事有关
Yeah, Cutty. She was on that shit, man.
这都一星期了McNulty
It's been a week, McNulty.
你在Stringer那儿要是没有进展  就得放弃了
Either you got something on Stringer or you don't.
他想卖一套公寓给我
He tried to sell me a condo.
鸟人一个
Cocksucker.
说不定还会让你进个高级俱乐部 学学高尔夫什么的
Might as well join the Rotary and take up golf or some shit.
他虽然是在遛猎狗玩 但肯定心里还惦记着打狐狸
He's running with the hounds, though I'll bet his heart is still with the fox.
Stringer退出江湖了?
Stringer's out of the game?
咱们Bell先生变成银行了
Mr. Bell has become the bank.
什么银行?
The bank?
走合法路线的银行
The bank plays it legit.
他制造可观的合法收入
He generates a good bit of honest income.
这些钱被用来购买那些 他自己永远都不会去碰的毒品
But at the same time, his money finances packages that he himself will never touch.
他不会再在道上出面
He won't go near the street.
他从街面上的买卖毒品生意中完全脱离出来
He's insulated from the everyday operations of the corner.
然后通过足够多的正当生意投资 把收上来的钱洗干净
The money that comes back is then laundered through enough straight business investments
而那些投资根本无迹可循
that there's no way to trace it.
高手到了这个境界
A player gets to that point,
警察就没有任何办法能抓到他的狐狸尾巴了
there ain't no way in hell a working police is going to tie a can to his tail.
真神了
Oh, man.
那么Kintel Williamson 这位巴尔的摩的王子
So, Kintel Williamson, the prince of Pimlico.
我们对这瘪三都掌握了些什么情况?
Where we at on this mope?
只弄到了两个一次性手机的号码
DNRs on a couple of payphones.
这样可以了么?
That got it?
不错
All right.
小子 你不过来帮下忙么?
You gonna help or what, boy?
又用不着我开枪 反正你们只是让我 他妈地在那该死的巷子里守着
Might as well not even take a whistle if all I'm doing is standing in the fucking alley.
你也只能呆在后面
Back's where you belong.
至少这样我就不用担心我的头会被打爆
Thataway I ain't got to be worrying about getting my damn head blown off...
Kimmy此话指责Tosha其实是由Dante所杀
具体参见S03E03 20分钟处 Tosha为额头中弹
因为你丫会吓得要命胡乱开枪
'cause you all scared and shit.
够了
Enough.
你们听到没有? 我说够了
Y'all hear me? I said enough.
你过来给这枪装上子弹 伙计
Come over here and put some pumpkin balls in this shotgun, man.
Kimmy!
你们俩都得学着习惯这一切 不然就退出
Both of y'all learn to live with it, or y'all out, man.
这次我们可不能再出什么差池了 你们听明白了吗
Now, this time we gonna do it right. Y'all feel me?
老大 你得放下这事 这样做不是办法
Boss, you gotta let this go. It ain't gonna work.
你上次在数据分析会不是说打对屁股才能出屎么
You said in COMSTAT shit rolls down.
我们已经试过跟那帮小混混们对话
Now, we tried to talk to all the hoppers.
他们什么也做不了主
What the hell can they do about anything?
我们要把这事捅到毒品分销商那儿去
We need to bring it to the dealers.
警司...
Sergeant...
我要一份所有在我辖区内 经营贩毒点的中层分销商名单
I need a list of names of all the mid -level dealers running my corners.
长官?
Sir?
警司 你负责为我收集数据 对不对? 我需要一份名字清单
You are my DEU, Sergeant, right? I need a list of names.
也许Narcotics市中心有这种东西 我可不清楚
Maybe Narcotics downtown has something like that. I don't know.
我们只负责逮人和收尸
We're knocking heads, taking bodies.
我不知道我还得做人口普查还有别的什么事情
I didn't know I was supposed to be doing a census or nothing.
哎 小姐 小姐 "尿壶"在哪里?
Hey, yo, miss. Miss, where the pee-pot at?
- 谢谢 - 来吧 走这边
- Thanks. - Come on, this way.
哎 我兄弟想做尿检
Yo, my man need to drop a negative.
好咧
Yeah.
5块钱
$5.
老王八 以前才2块钱
Motherfucker, they was just $2.
你自己去试试在巴尔的摩找合格的尿 5块一瓶拿走
You try finding clean piss in Baltimore. $5 a go.
- 哎 你怎么保证这一定没问题? - 我上托儿所弄来的
- Yo, how I know it's clean? - I get mine from daycare.
你帮我把鸡放到烤箱里 温度设在华氏375度
I need you to put the chicken in the oven at 375.
对 把这做完之后 把我妹妹放到...
Yes, and after you're done that, I need you to help me put your sister down...
打扰一下 女士
Excuse me, miss.
拇指放在扫描仪上
Put your thumb on the scanner.
按在那儿别动
Hold on a second.
- 你的名字? - 姓Wise 全名Dennis Wise
- What's your name? - Wise, Dennis Wise.
拿一个瓶子 转角过去第二个门
Take one of those. Go around the corner to the second door.
不行 你不能到外面去
No, you cannot go outside.
你有没有在听我说啊?
Are you listening to what I'm saying?
我们所知的西区毒贩全在这上面了
That's all we got on the Westside dealers.
George 这本子里只有逮捕记录
George. I'm looking at a sprinkling of rap sheets here.
你是想告诉我这个部门里再也没有人知道
Well, you telling me nobody in this department know...
谁在控制巴尔的摩的贩毒点了么?
who controls West Baltimore corners anymore?
Rawls让我的人去管街上抽大麻的
Hey, Rawls has my people doing street rips.
你想要最新的资料 应该去找情报处
You want up-to-date info, you should try the intelligence unit.
- 靠 他们让我来找你 George - 我他妈能告诉你什么?
- Shit, they sent me to you, George. - What the fuck can I tell you?
所有人都在忙着维持街道秩序 哪有人还有空管那些高端贩毒的事情
With all the street work, ain't nobody left doing the high-end drug stuff.
据我所知 那个人自己开个雅阁车 特意过来帮我们
From what I'm hearing, the guy comes in of his own accord...
我们却辜负了他
and he gets betrayed by us.
这个城市没有提供给他任何保护措施 所谓的对他有所安排
Protection in this city amounts to nothing more than getting dumped...
就是让他被弃尸在40号公路边上的 一家低级旅店里
in a fleabag joint on Route 40 and calling it a plan.
没有人监视 没有人帮他
No monitoring, no assistance.
啥都没有 只有一堆衣服和一把牙刷
Nothing. Just a bundle of clothes and a toothbrush.
- 天哪 - 不应该这样对待一个跟我们合作的人
- Jesus. - No way to treat a cooperator.
我知道有人可能会四处奔走把这事向媒体张扬
I know someone could get a lot of mileage out of this with the press.
但我们才不管那么多呢 因为如果我走这条途径
But fuck that, right, because if I go that way...
那么每个人都会忙着为自己辩护 而事情却得不到解决
then everybody gets defensive and nothing gets fixed.
所以我来把这事跟你直说了
I'm coming to you with this, straight up.
你说得对
Agreed.
这件事处理到哪一步了
Where do we stand on this?
我们已经向州检察官提出就此事召开会议
You've already called for a meeting on this with the state's attorney...
警察局长也通知到了
and the Police Commissioner.
时间就定在下个星期三
It's penciled in for next Wednesday.
不 不 Tommy已经在调查这事了 我们要赶快行动
No, no, Tommy's right on this. We need to act quickly.
我很高兴你来跟我们商量这事
I'm glad you came to us with this.
我会让这事明确解决的 相信我
I'll light a fire, believe me.
好 谢谢
All right, thanks.
- 你会随时通告我这事进展情况的吧? - 当然 绝对的 议员您请慢走
- You will keep me in the loop on this? - Yeah, absolutely. Councilman.
嘿 别走那么快 美眉 我们来聊几句
Hey, slow up, girlfriend, we need to talk for a minute.
- 是啊 小甜妞 - 我们认识么?
- Yeah, sweet thing. - We met before?
不认识 宝贝 不过可能以后就认识了
No, baby, but that can happen.
既然不认识 那我就恕不奉陪了
We ain't met, excuse me.
- 哎 就聊几句嘛 宝贝儿 - 别挡老娘的道
- Hey, it's just talk, baby. - Get the fuck out the way.
姐们儿 我们只是想跟你谈几句...
Look, girl, all we need for you to do is talk...
你是聋了还是大麻抽傻了?
Is you deaf or just stone stupid?
别介呀 姐们儿 我们只是想...
Look, hold on, girl, all we wanna do...
见鬼
Damn.
现在 我们要谈点事了
Now, we gonna talk.
你们这个小不起眼的部门怎么他妈的 就能搞到所有这些毒品情报呢?
How the fuck is this little runt of a unit holding all this drug intelligence?
我在总部兜了无数圈子什么屁也没得到
I made the rounds down at headquarters and came up with jack...
而你们却掌握着所有这些
and y'all holding all this.
只要你放几个窃听器 很快就能把资料柜填满了
Well, you run a couple of wiretaps, you fill up a file cabinet pretty fast.
这太棒了 谢谢
This is great. Thanks.
不是吧!
Oh, shit!
好久不见!
God damn it!
我听说你到这儿落脚了
I heard this was where you landed.
这小帅哥 是我最先用上的
This pretty boy, I broke his ass in.
那时小毛头一个人所用的掩护身份 要比整个特警队用到的都多
I wrote more on ID complaints on Bushy-top here than on the whole goddamn squad.
就这么着 他凭着自己的实力一步步升上去了
That is, till he scuffed himself up.
现在你在哪儿盯着呢?
Now where you at, McNulty?
南克林顿街1911号 一楼
1911 South Clinton Street, first floor.
这就对了
There you go.
嗯 我就知道你会紧跟着他的...
Yeah. I know you got to keep him close...
不管怎么说 这孩子绝对是个好警察
but still, that's a good goddamn police right here.
是什么风把你吹到这儿来了?
So what brings you to our shop?
我想知道谁在我的辖区内经营贩毒点
I'm trying to find out who running my corners.
我自己的数据库里只能找到街上抽大麻的人
My own DEU is just about street rips,
到总部也什么都没找着
and headquarters wasn't no help, neither.
不过你们帮了我大忙了
Y'all saved my ass, though.
你告诉他有关你盯的那小子Marlo的事没?
You tell him about your boy Marlo?
那都在文件里了 跟其他我们所知的中级毒贩资料在一起
It's in the files, along with every other mid-level player we know.
我可不可以问下 警长 你打算拿这些资料干什么呢?
You don't mind me asking, what are you gonna do with all that, Major?
这个嘛...
Well...
我们会让这些小青年围成一圈
we'll round up these young men...
然后给他们的屁股 都贴上个电脑数据分析的标签
and put a little COMSTAT on their ass.
走了 先生们 女士 小毛头
Gentlemen. Ma'am. Bushy-top.
小毛头?
Bushy-top?
* 新一天联合机构欢迎你 明日的成功故事始于今日 * 总裁旅店
计算订货点数云云
Uh, point of order and shit.
由主席表扬Veronica大道上 最受尊敬的营销人员
Chair recognize the esteemed rep of the Veronica Avenue boys.
行了 我们在这些废话上浪费的时间够久的了
All right, look, we done talked this shit to death, all right?
- 啥时候投票吧? - Rick说出了我们的心声
- When we gonna vote? - Rick do have a point.
那好 所有同意我们一起干
All right, then. All those in favor of going together...
以便让纽约区的这张订单 能获得最优惠折扣的 请举手
so we can get the best discount on a New York package, raise up.
那好 就这样决定了
All right, then. There it is.
钱会越来越多 大家一起赚吧
Look like we gonna make more money, together.
我得说 我真为你们感到骄傲 你们能放下那些小气叽歪
Got to say I'm proud of y'all for putting aside petty grievances...
联合起来促成此事
and putting this thing together.
你们这一帮冷血打杀惯了的黑社会
For a cold-ass crew of gangsters,
居然把这件事搞得跟共和党竞选似的
y'all carried it like Republicans and shit.
兄弟 记着 等你向他们扔砖头的时候 可别忘了说这些屁话
Yo, remember, man, talk this shit up when you hit them bricks.
让更多的人加入的最好办法 就是让大家知道这件事能带来的好处
Best way to get more involved is to tell people about the benefits of this here thing.
我们不发牢骚 不搞闹剧 纯粹做生意
No beefing, no drama, just business.
如果这当中有人跟其他人有过节的
Anybody got problems with anybody else here
我们拿出来集体讨论解决
we bring it to the group.
不要把矛盾搞到街面上去
We ain't gotta take it to the streets.
好了 就这么做吧
All right. Let's do it.
小子
Yo.
王八羔子 这是什么?
Motherfucker, what is that?
根据办公规则大全 开会不是应该写会议纪要吗?
The Robert Rules say we gotta have minutes for a meeting, right?
这是会议纪要
These the minutes.
死黑鬼 这他妈的是犯罪密谋会议 你记个什么鬼笔记啊?
Nigga, is you taking notes on a criminal fucking conspiracy?
你他妈的脑子进水了?
What the fuck is you thinking, man?
- 太棒了 - 爸 他在作弊
- That's cool. - Dad, he's cheating.
Michael 跟你弟弟别那么较真
Michael, take it easy on your brother.
你们俩跟你妈的新朋友相处得怎么样?
How are you two getting along with Mom's new friend?
我们叫他Dennis 他不算是新人了
We call him Dennis. He's not new.
好吧 你们跟他和得来么?
Okay, how are you doing with him?
妈说我们不能跟你讲家里的事
Mom says we can't talk to you about family stuff.
爸 校园开放日你会来么?
Dad, you going to the open house?
我尽量吧 不过我最近工作真的好忙
Yeah, I'll try. I've been real busy at work though.
办新案子还有好多别的事
New case and all.
爸 妈说你必须要来
Mom says you have to go, Dad.
是啊 其他所有小孩的爸爸都会来的
Yeah, all the other kids' fathers are gonna be there.
抓他的腿
Get his legs.
王八蛋 竟敢偷我们的东西?
Steal from us, motherfucker, huh?
把他戒指也拿下来
Get the ring, too, yo.
- 拔不下来啊 - 放倒他
Shit won't come off, yo. Drop him.
你们知道这人是为我们做事的
You know the man works for us.
你们继续这样对他对大家都没什么好处
You keep going at him like that ain't gonna be nothing
放了他让他想办法赔回来就好
left of him to make right what he owes.
总得让这鸟人付出点代价
Bitch got to pay.
- 来 翻他的口袋 - 对
- Hey, yo, check his pockets, yo. - Right.
这混合烟卷儿归我了 滚! 你给我滚开!
That dog's mine, yo. Fuck off! Get the fuck off!
你们好啊?
What's up, baby?
我说小子 我在里面呆了26个月 你他妈居然开个破福特车来接我?
Yo, man, I been in here for 26 months... you come pick me up in a motherfucking Ford?
我跟你闹着玩呢 你好啊 兄弟
I'm just fucking with you. What's up, baby?
你还好吧 哥们儿?
What up, man?
哥们儿 能从这鬼地方出来 我感觉真太好了 你知道吗
Man, I'm feeling real good to be out of this motherfucker. You know what?
你知道不 这门的另外一边有块牌子 上面写着 永远不再
There's a sign on the other side of this gate that say, "Never again."
这是我唯一打算从这个鬼地方带走的东西
And that's the only fucking thing I'm gonna take with me from this place.
别的都先别说了 兄弟 我们先把你的形象收拾收拾
First things first, man. Let's get you looking right.
- 你知道我的意思吧? - 你们把我的行头拿来了
- You know what I mean? - You got my shit.
没错 没错 形象要好看才行
Oh, yes. Yes. Good looking, baby.
从一分区开始
Start with Sector One.
下班前尽量把所有人都带到Vincent街附近
Bring as many as you can down to the Vincent Street area by the end of the shift.
不要开押人的车去
Don't use your wagons.
把他们尽量都塞到小车里带走
Bring as many as you can in your cars.
连那些小混混都不听话 你怎么能肯定这些人会听你的呢?
The hoppers wouldn't listen. What makes you think these guys will?
经营贩毒点的人都相当于咱们的警司级别了
These are lieutenants running the corners...
我对他们的痛苦感同身受
and I personally feel their pain.
中层管理意味着你有相当的责任
Now, middle-management means that you have just enough responsibility...
需要去倾听别人的意见
that you got to listen when people talk...
但却没有相当的权力 可以让别人去屌他们自己
and not so much...that you can tell anybody to go fuck themselves.
听着 我们警长只是想跟你们谈个话 仅此而已 我可以保证
Look, my major just wants to talk. That's all, I promise.
我们会把你们好好地送回这里的
We'll bring you right back.
恕难从命
That ain't gonna happen.
你丫说什么呢?
What the fuck you say?
你什么意思 说什么恕难从命?
What the fuck you mean, it ain't gonna happen?
你给我好好听着 王八蛋
Let me tell you something, motherfucker.
我们头儿下令让把你们这些不长眼的家伙 带回局里去跟他坐一坐
We got orders to bring your sorry ass... down the way for a sit down with our boss.
所以我们现在就准备把你们给带走
Now we're prepared to take you with us right now.
想要我们来软的还是...
We can either do this the easy way...
- 榆木脑袋还挺硬的 - 你们自己决定
- Brain-dead fucks. - It's up to you.
- 喂 - Prez 是我
- Hello. - Prez, it's me.
我想这边可能有点棘手 别挂线 换频道
I think we got a little situation here. Stay with me. 10-6.
警长点名要找你们 你们就得去
Major wants the dickhead, you gotta go.
他这次不想去就算了
I think he gets a pass this time.
你确定么? 你想要他去 他就得去
You sure? I mean, you want, he goes.
这次先放过他吧 Herc
Another time, Herc.
警长的时间我们可耗不起
We're on the Major's clock here.
好好认住这张脸 臭王八蛋 我明天还会来的
Don't forget the face, cocksucker. It's gonna be here tomorrow.
要不要我呼叫总部支援?
You need me to call dispatch?
不用 没事 我回头再跟你说
No, it's okay. I'll tell you later.
我看还是把警队开过来 好好教训教训这帮混蛋
I say we get the troops and fuck these assholes up.
来 我们再打一盘
Come on, let's go again.
别这样 Tommy 一场比赛而已
Come on, Tommy, it's just a game.
听你这么说 反正你都已经得到你想要的了
Look, sounds like you got what you want, anyway.
我是指从市长那里
From the Mayor, I mean.
是又怎么样 他以前还耍过我呢
Yeah, well, he's played me before.
老子发誓 如果这件事他不好好处理
But so help me if he farts around on this
我一定不会放过他 非给他来点狠的不可
I'm going after him. Big time.
- 你来真的? - 绝对是真的
- For real? - Trust me on this.
他三番五次推我下水
He keeps ducking me,
我得让他尝尝我的厉害了
I'm gonna fuck him good.
这是好的一部分
That's the good part.
我管这叫胡萝卜
It's what I call the carrot.
你们把你们的人迁到任何我刚才所说的指定区域
Now you move your people into any designated area I told you about...
你们就等于拿到免捕和免诉的护身令牌
and you'll have immunity from arrest and prosecution.
你们可以自由地送你们的货 收该收的东西 没人会干涉你们
You're free to make your drops, collect what need collecting won't nobody bother you.
我说话算话
You got my word on it.
这样做对你有什么好处?
What do you get out of this?
这个问题提得好
That's a fair question.
我要补救我的辖区里任何还值得补救事情
I want to salvage what's still worth salvaging in my district.
但要是任由一大帮小混混到处撒野 搞得人心惶惶的话
And I can't do that with a bunch of young hoppers running around...
我就什么事都做不来
scaring the hell out of decent people.
这些小孩不会听我指挥 但他们听你们的
Now, these kids ain't gonna listen to me, but they will listen to y'all.
假如你们告诉他们迁到这边来 把买卖开到这里 他们一定照办
Now, you tell them to move down here, set up a shop, and they will.
这就是我打算做的
So the way I got it figured,
我来鼓动你们 你们去鼓动他们
I motivate you and you motivate them.
不 这是个陷阱
No, this is a trap.
不是的 你们查一下这地方
No, you check out the spot.
没有摄像头 没有录音话筒 什么也没有
There ain't no cameras, ain't no microphones, nothing.
任何你们所能看到的警察 只会出现在划区界线以外
Any cops you see going to be down right on the perimeter.
他们的职责只是为了防止暴力事件的发生
Just to make sure there's no violence.
而且你们可以看着
And you watch.
看他们是否按我所说的方式操作
You see if it don't work out the way I say.
警长 我们不是想跟你对着干
Nothing personal against you, Chief...
但万一我们要是不合作会怎么样?
but what happens if we buck?
你们还记得我说的胡萝卜吧?
You remember the carrot, right?
如果你们选择大棒的话
Well, you choose the stick instead...
那你们将要尝尝前所未有的大棒滋味了
you gonna feel that stick like you ain't never felt before.
我们会每天出动 到每一个贩毒点找你们的麻烦
We gonna indict every corner, every day.
我手下有200多号警员
I got over 200 sworn personnel,
我打算让他们什么别的事都不做 尽其所能地去把你们每一个人都敲掉
and I plan to free up every one of them to knock every one of y'all down they can.
你们是在我的辖区里开点贩毒 想要低调 没门
You're on a corner in my district, it ain't gonna be about no humble...
想要只被控游荡罪 没门 没那些好事
it ain't gonna be about no loitering charge, nothing like that.
你们就等着圣经上的那些话
There gonna be some biblical shit happening to you
应验在你们走向监狱大篷车的时候吧 听懂了吗?
on the way to that motherfucking jail wagon. You understand me?
而在你们跟新系统搞对抗的时候
And while you're bucking the new system,
你们当中的聪明人会在这边
the smart ones among you... gonna be down here,
大把大把地赚着快钱
making money hand over fist.
好好想想吧
So think it over.
但我向老天保证 到了下个星期一
But I swear to God, come Monday...
你我的世界将会大不相同
your world and mine ain't gonna be the same.
你不是说这些房子里都他妈的空着没人住吗?
I thought you said these goddamn houses were vacant.
我们可能是把她给漏了
We must have missed her.
这样一来我还要再多做一件事
There's one more thing I gotta do then.
住上面B层的那个小个子 他的其中一个小弟是在宿舍区住的
Little man, up on B tier, one of his boys in the dormitory...
他的哥哥跟射伤警察的 那个男孩的女朋友关系很磁
his brother's tight with the girlfriend of the boy that shot that police.
小个子说
Little man saying,
"如果你让我们三个都爽了 我们就可以让她开口"
"If you sprung the three of us... "we can get her talking."
你知道 就是说找到那把枪
You know, find the gun.
哥们儿 我听说有个叫Dink的小孩 手上有那个人的枪
Yo, I'm hearing the boy, Dink, got that man's gun.
我现在还不能肯定那个Dink是 Dink Dink还是
Now, I ain't sure yet if that Dink be... Dink Dink or
墨Dink 或者可能是肥Dink
Inky Dink or maybe Fat Dink.
再有可能会是 扁鼻Dink 不对 等一下
Then again, it might be Flatnose Dink. No, wait.
不 不 不可能是扁鼻Dink 他已经死了
Nah, nah, that can't be him, that Dink dead.
哥们儿 不是我不想帮你
Look, man, I can help you.
但你得让我从这些谋杀案的控罪里脱身才行
But first you gotta get me out from under these murder beefs.
哦 你所说的谋杀案有多少单?
Yeah. How many murders are we talking?
哥们儿 那一定得是警察的枪么?
Look, man, do it have to be the cop's gun?
如果你只是想要枪的话 我可以帮你搞到枪
'Cause if it's guns you want, I can get you guns.
我记得这学校
I remember this.
6年级 Holley太太的科学课
Sixth grade. Mrs. Holley's science class.
盒装午餐 难吃得要命
Box lunches. Taste like shit.
你有什么事这么重要 就不能通过正常渠道来让我知道么?
You got something so important, man, you can't go through the proper channels?
哦 不是的 怎么说呢
Well, no. I don't know.
我只是想如果我不是告诉你而其他人 你可能会想我是在胡说八道
I just figured if I told anybody but you, you might think I'm riding the rock.
你怎么让我相信你不是呢?
What makes me think you ain't?
对 你说得有道理
Yeah, right. That's a good point.
是这样的 今天 我还有Tuckie和Little Mikey
Look, today, me, Tuckie, Little Mikey...
我们所有的一大帮人被警察抓起来了
man, we all, a bunch of us got scooped up by the police.
你们就不该卖毒品嘛
Well, you shouldn't sell drugs.
好吧 好吧
All right, all right.
不是啦 他们没有把我们带到局子里去
Nah, see, they didn't take us to the station.
他们把我们带到Vincent街最底那一段
They took us down to the bottom of Vincent Street...
那儿的房子都给围起来了 然后他们放了我们
where all the houses is boarded up, and they let us out.
还有 别的先不提
And then, on top of all of that, like,
他们的态度忽然之间都变得特和蔼可亲起来
the whole while they was being all like decent and shit,
你知道 这让我感觉特别扭
and you know that fucked me up.
然后 他们的警长走出来
And then, like, the police chief, he come out...
接下来的才是最不可思议的
and this is the crazy part...
他说他设定好了一定的范围 让我们可以卖东西
he say that he got it set up so where we could sell stuff in certain spots,
警察不会来干涉我们
and the police won't bother us.
我知道 我知道 这太让人摸不着头脑了
I know, I know. It's fucked up...
但我就想着你应该知道这事儿
but I just thought you should know.
- 就这么多了? - 对 就这些 还有Marlo那小子还没搞定哦
- That's it? - Yeah, just that and the boy Marlo.
对 我知道该怎么处理
Yeah, I'm on it.
没错
Yep.
23-03呼叫信息中心
23-03 to KGA.
请让F队用第6频道跟我联系
Have Foxtrot meet me on six, Adam.
- F队明白 - 23-03号呼叫F队
- Foxtrot, 10-4. - 23-03 to Foxtrot.
F队 待命中
Foxtrot, standing by.
那是一辆黑色奔驰 正从停车场开出来
It's a black Mercedes, pulling out the lot.
收到 我们盯住它了
Copy that, we got the eyeball.
是在这儿么?
This here the spot?
听Tuckie说我们应该在这里开店做生意
'Cause Tuckie says we supposed to set up shop here.
Hamsterdam
Hamsterdam.
对 就是这儿
Yeah, this is it.
只要是在我们插的小白旗范围内 里面任何位置你们都可以开点
Set up anywhere inside where we got the white flags.
哎 我们打算撤了
Yo, I'm getting ready to roll out.
你们才刚来 怎么回事?
You just got here. What's wrong?
这周围没人买东西
Ain't nobody around to buy.
说得好
Good point.
- 人家需要顾客 - 可不是嘛
- Man needs customers. - I'm saying...
不行 你不能让我做这个 我他妈可是堂堂的一名警务人员啊
No. I mean, you can't make me. I'm a sworn fucking police officer.
老子级别高过你 乖乖地照办吧
你好吗? 你还有那种小袋子吧?
What's up, man? You got that Body Bag still?
来两个
Two.
警察
Narco.
交出来 王八蛋 把钱还给他 马上
Give it up, motherfucker. Money comes back, right now.
老大 你们搞乱套了吧 我不是得先用上了 你们才能抓我的吗
Boss, you fucking up, man. You didn't let me cop before you snatch me up.
这才是规矩吗?
Is that some fucking rule?
电话到 拖车到
You call, we haul.
- 你没吸毒吧? - 是啊 我当然没有啦
- You clean? - Yeah, of course I'm clean.
傻冒差佬 还没给我机会用上点呢
Stupid-ass rookie didn't even give me a chance to cop.
这个街角被管制了
This corner's indicted.
你要么搬去Vincent街 要么等我们带铐子回来找你
You move over to Vincent Street, or we come back with the bracelets.
- 你有什么发现? - 我在Riggs与Calhoun街交界处 请确认频率
- What you got? - 10-11 me at Riggs and Calhoun.
尽管发生了未能预期的延迟
Despite unforeseen delays...
我们将在一月开始学校课程
we will begin an academy class this January
因此我们看好来年的发展
which leaves us in good shape for the coming year.
谢谢你 局长先生
Thank you, Commissioner.
主席先生请等一下 我有几个问题
The chair pleases, I have a couple of questions.
局长先生 我想你已经知道
Commissioner, I know that you are aware
一名州里的证人在最近 市里的凶杀案审理过程中被杀
that a state witness in a recent city homicide prosecution was killed.
我们对这件事是以最高优先级处理的
We are treating that incident with the highest priority.
凶案科已经组织了专案小组
Homicide has set up a task force...
毒品科正从线人方面寻找线索
and Narcotics is working the informant angle.
我们还向FBI和药品管理局请求援助
We have also asked both the FBI and DEA for support.
听起好象媒体新闻稿
It sounds like a full-court press,
但你得承认这有点像是马后炮
but you must admit it's a bit like closing the barn door after the horse is out.
我是说 男生在Lake Clifton高中停车场被枪杀
I mean, the shooting of the boy on a lot at Lake Clifton High School...
本来就是一桩高级别的案子 对不对 局长先生?
was a high-profile case, wasn't it, Commissioner?
停止
的确是的
Yes, it was.
然而案中一名关键的目击证人被允许... 请稍等一下
And yet a key witness in the case was allowed... One moment.
很抱歉 局长先生 主席先生刚刚好心提醒我
Excuse me, Commissioner, but the chair was good enough to remind me...
说您另外有一个媒体会议安排
that you have a pressing engagement.
所以如果您不介意的话 我们可以稍后再继续这个话题
So if it's all right with you, we can continue this at a later date.
休会
Meeting adjourned.
你看到Burrell满头大汗的样子没?
Did you see Burrell sweat?
他的领子都快化了
The man's collar almost melted.
你这是在搞什么鬼?
What the hell got into you?
是你 老朋友 这是你搞起来的
You did, old buddy. You did.
终点站到 都下车吧
End of the line, all out.
我们有Rockefeller
We got that Rockefeller, yo.
我们这边有Rockefeller
We got that Rockefeller over here, yo.
- 来这边我们有Rockefeller - 搞什么飞机?
- Over here we got that Rockefeller, yo. - What the fuck?
朋友 朋友 我们有Rockefeller哎
Yo, yo, we got that Rockefeller, yo.
我们有WMD 就在这儿 就在这儿
We got that WMD. Right here, right here.
WMD原指大型杀伤性武器 此处双关指毒品很够劲
我听说WMD很给力哦
I hear the WMD is the bomb.
WMD
WMD.
给我两份 哥们儿
Give me two, yo.
WMD 这儿有卖
WMD. Right here.
WMD 这儿有卖 这儿有卖
WMD, right here. Right here.
这儿有卖的
Right here.
我们这里有洛克弗勒 大哥
We got that Rockefeller over here. Yo.
大哥
Yo.
卖Rockefeller喽
We got that Rockefeller, yo.
- 情况如何? - 地上有个双筒望远镜
- What do we got? - There's binoculars on the floor.
- Marlo打算行动了? - 耐心等着看吧
- Marlo making a move? - Just watch.
那个男孩 Bodie跟你说的一切事情 你都别放在心上
Forget everything the boy Bodie told you.
打他们的事也忘掉吧 我来不是为那个的
Forget the beating, it ain't about that.
你很聪明 我能看得出来
You smart, man, I can see that.
我本想着让你选个安全的地方好让我们说说话
I wanted you to choose somewhere safe for us to speak.
但是 他妈的
But God damn...
这儿的窃听器比虫子还多
only bugs in this motherfucker gonna have legs.
我呢 挺欣赏聪明人的
Now, I appreciate smart...
但是你要知道 在江湖上想混下去 只凭小聪明是不够的
but you gotta know in this game, man, it ain't enough.
你学过历史么?
You a student of history?
你知不知道这个城市出过很多的聪明人?
You know this town had its share of smart players, man?
Melvin, Little Wil,Big Head Brother
Melvin, Little Wil, Big Head Brother,
Peanut, Warren
Peanut, Warren.
他们都非常聪明 非常聪明
All real smart, man, real smart.
但是呢 他们一打响名头
But you know, soon as their names rang out...
联邦调查局就找上他们了
the feds was on them.
你明白我在说什么吗? 政府不想让你们组织起来
You know what I mean? Government ain't want you to be organized.
不 他们希望你们又吝啬又好斗
No, they want you scrimping and scraping,
为了帮派之间一些鸡毛蒜皮的事情互相残杀
killing each other on the corner on some bullshit.
我可不这样
Not me.
所以我跟Prop Joe一起 打算把这个黑帮联合机构搞起来
That's why me and Prop Joe, we getting ready to put this co-op together.
不同的团伙 一张整合订单 拿到最好的海洛因 最好的可卡因
Different crews, one package. Best dope, best coke.
平均分配
Share and share alike.
- 我听人说过这事 - 你听说过这事?
- Been hearing about that. - You been hearing about that?
这就好 这算是一个好的开始 对吧?
That's good. That's a start, right?
你在外面开着的那辆奔驰车
You know that Mercedes you got riding out there, man...
有没有让你姨妈或别的什么亲戚帮你挂名?
you got that titled in your aunt's name or some shit?
要知道 如果他们想找你的麻烦
Now, when they come get you,
你花的那点小钱买的玩意儿 就会带给你老大的麻烦 小兄弟
that straw purchase out there gonna come bite you in the ass, boy.
这就是他们的做法
That's what they do.
你的钱会被他们利用来整回你自己
They turn your money against you.
现在你呢 我想凭你控制着的那些个街角
Now, you, I'm thinking with the corners that you got...
应该有接近一百万的收入吧?
you close to $1 mil, right?
还好啦
I'm doing all right.
你是做得还好
You doing all right,
但还好不到能让你的名字被镶在镜框里吧?
but all right ain't got your name on a crib, right?
也还好不到 能带给你一小块地方让你洗你的黑钱
Ain't got you a little spot for you to wash that dirty money.
而这些是我所能提供给你的
That what I'm offering you, man.
- 说嘛 他跟谁在那里面? - 我说了 耐心点继续看着
- Come on, who's he in there with? - I told you, keep watching.
Bunk让你跟进这单案子的?
Bunk put you up to this?
要不这样吧 我用一箱你爱喝的蓝带啤酒
Tell you what, how about a case of that PBR piss you drink...
跟你赌点爱尔兰啤酒 我赌他已经从后门出去了
against a touch of the Irish that he went out the back...
你现在盯着的那房子里什么也没有
and you're watching that house for nothing.
你的什么也没有出来了
Here comes your nothing.
哇!
Whoa!
蓝带啤酒我喜欢喝瓶装的
I like my piss in bottles.
你喜欢什么样的都可以 亲爱的
Anyway you like, darling.
Chris
Chris.
告诉咱们的人都拿上家伙
Tell our people to tool up.
我这就去办
I'm on it.
来买WMD啊 快来买WMD
I got that WMD. Got that WMD.
他们很快就适应下来了
They get comfortable with it pretty quick.
可不是 就好象我们根本不存在一样
Yeah, it's like we ain't even standing here.
小混混们管这儿叫Hamsterdam
The hoppers call it Hamsterdam.
发音接近阿姆斯特丹
Like from Amsterdam.
Hamsterdam
Hamsterdam.
通过把各种数学概念综合在一起
By the use of integrated math concepts
例如代数的推理和数感 几何学 概率学等
such as algebraic reasoning and number sense, geometry and probability.
真不错
Very impressive.
我们尽量把每个班的人数 控制在10人以下 不超过12人
Now what we try to do is keep the class size under 10, 12 at the very most.
- 而且还分成三个层次 - 对 所以如果...
- And there are three levels? - Yes, so that if...
抱歉 我是Jim McNulty
Sorry, I'm Jim McNulty.
我来晚了一点 被工作上的事情拖延了
I'm a little late, 'cause of developments at work.
McNulty先生
Mr. McNulty.
我对这个综合数学计划有些担心
I have some concerns about the integrated math program.
在学前班里 Michael上过代数入门
In their previous schools, Michael took introductory algebra...
但我想在你们学校里会教不同的东西
but I understand that this school is doing something different.
- 是的 这个综合数学计划... - 对不起 我有些口渴
- We are. The integrated math program... - Excuse me, I'm thirsty.
你们谁要喝点什么么?
Can I get either of you something to drink?
这个综合数学计划里包括...
The integrated math program here consists...
虽然没多少好吃的 但大家都喜欢这些生蔬果
Not much of a spread, but you can't go wrong with crudity.
生食与粗糙是同一个字 这里McNulty故意装理解错误
粗糙?
Crudity?
对不起 你知道 我直接下了班过来的 不然的话我会换身衣服的
I'm sorry. You know, I came straight from work, or I'd have changed.
这里不用点名吧?
No need to call names, right?
您做哪一行? 贵姓?
What do you do, Mr...
我是雷格梅森基金公司董事会成员 Jim McNulty
I'm on the board at Legg Mason. Jim McNulty.
雷格梅森基金公司?
Legg Mason?
不是在这家公司干就是在本市当警察 我老是想不起来
Either that or I'm a cop in the city. I keep forgetting.
我是Terri D'Agostino
Terri D'Agostino.
我是本校的前校友 也是本校一名可怕的基金募集者
I'm an alumni and one of the school's dreaded fundraisers.
这个数学计划可以提供学习辅导
The math program offers tutoring possibilities.
这样如果Michael觉得适应不过来
So if Michael finds it difficult adjusting...
我们可以把课安排在星期二和星期四
we can have classes on Tuesdays and Thursdays.
你觉得这间学校怎么样?
So how do you find the school?
- 挺好的 - 那就好
- It's good. - Good.
我前妻跟我在考虑把两个儿子送到这里来上学
My ex and I are thinking of sending our boys here.
- 有什么问题或困难吗? - 没有 没什么大不了的
- Any problems, difficulties? - No, not really.
只是 我的长子要学的那个综合数学
I mean, there's the math integration class for my oldest.
他现在在上六七年级
He's in sixth, seventh, and...
我不太确定他是否准备好应付那么多的数学
I'm just not sure he's ready, you know, for all that math.
轻着点 我只是一个乡下男孩
Careful, I'm only a country boy.
给我闭嘴!
Shut up.
嘿 哥们儿 欢迎归来
Hey, sweetie, welcome home.
你好吗?
How's it going?
怎么样 哥们儿 一切都好吧?
What's up, man? How you doing?
欢迎归来
Welcome back.
大姐
Hey, sis.
天哪 我真希望回家来的不止我一个人 你懂的
Man, I just wish I wasn't the only one coming home, you know.
我明白
I know.
今晚好好享受 我们过后再聊
Enjoy tonight. We'll talk later.
- 欢迎回家 - Prop你好 近来可好?
- Welcome home. - What up, Prop? How you doing, man?
都挺好 你体型保持得不错嘛
All right. You looking fit.
操 当然啦 我在那里面一直做健身呢 那儿除了健身之外没别的事可做了
Hell, yeah, I've been working out in there. That's all you gonna do, is work out.
倒像是个好地方能让一个胖人 找到他的内在自我
Might be a good place for a fat man to find his inner self.
哥们儿
Yo.
我有几个城里的西装朋友 想用很短一点时间跟你诉诉衷肠
I got some downtown suits who wanna holler at you real quick.
带我去会什么西装朋友啊 我想会那些穿裙子的!
Take me to see suits, I'm trying to see some skirts.
那么你是做什么的呢?
So what do you do?
你穿好衣服走吧
You should get dressed.
我这会儿有好多工作要做 明天还有很多事要处理
I got a lot of work here. It's a long day for me tomorrow.
我会非常安静的
I'll be really quiet.
说不定 你工作闷了想消遣消遣
You never know, you might get bored working.
我该工作了
I gotta work.
你也该走了
You gotta go.
Avon你知道 Stringer已经把市中心的 那些房产都搞到手里了
What Stringer has done with all that property downtown, Avon...
一旦政府的土地重新发展的资金到位
I cannot tell the kind of profit you're looking at...
你们的收益将是不可想像的
once all the federal redevelopment money lands.
到时整条Howard街都会被推平
That whole Howard Street thing is gonna take off...
你们就等着在那儿分蛋糕吧
and you're gonna be right there to cut the pie yourself.
你们现在投入的每一分钱 到时都会有十倍的回报
Any dollar you spend now is gonna come back to you 10 times.
还有一点 我知道你不想再回到街上去混
And the thing is, I know you don't wanna go back to them streets.
经历过这么多 你肯定想做点别的
Not after what you been through.
我懂的 因为我也同样是在街上混过的
I know, 'cause I'm from them same streets.
所以一旦我有机会转做别的
And once I had the chance to play a different game...
我脑子里对应该怎么做清楚得很
it wasn't a question in my mind how to go.
政府也将会死死盯着你的一举一动
The government is going to be looking at you hard, too.
没理由让他们得偿心愿
No sense in giving them what they're looking for.
你拿出你所拥有的 然后就地发展你的事业
You take what you have, you build on it.
我都知道了 定个日子吧
It's all good. Just put it up on the calendar.
我们再见面详谈
We should meet.
哎 Slim 你看到那两个黑鬼了么?
Yo, Slim. You see them two niggas right there?
他们在那边过毒瘾也不管周围是什么环境
They over there getting high in the middle of all this.
他妈的都没人守规则了吗?
Now where the fucking discipline at, yo?
操 把那俩黑鬼给我扔出去
Fuck, toss them niggas.
我能跟你说句话么? 你真不该用那种眼神盯着我看
Can I talk to you for a second? Don't you know not to stare at me like that?
哎 哥们儿
Hey, yo.
我得让你看些东西 对不起了 美女
I gotta show you something. Pardon me, sweetie.
我说 哥们儿  你知道我已经被关了那么久啊 唉
Yo, man. You know I've been locked down, man.
你会非常喜欢这个的 相信我
You gonna love this. Trust me.
好啊
Okay.
不错
Yeah.
靠 这可一点也不像 我在Jessup住的那个小窝
Shit, this ain't my little place down in Jessup.
但你知道我的意思 谁还惦记它啊
But you know what I mean, what the fuck is, right?
这全是你的了 B
This is all you, B.
全都属于你 而且是以你的名字买下的
All you, in your name, too.
你知道我的意思吗? 这份文件就是合法的证明
You know what I mean? This piece of paper right here make it legit.
这钥匙是林肯领航员的 就停在地下车库里
Keys to the Navigator in the basement.
这车只是先租着 等你自己挑到好车再退
It's just a rental until you pick out something nice.
靠 这么多好东西?
Damn, all this, huh?
你做得不错
You did good.
是啊 我们现在挣了那么多的正路钱
Yeah, I mean we're making so much straight money, man...
我们可以公开地买这些东西 挂我们自己的名字上去
we can carry shit like this out in the open, in our own names.
你还记得我们以前常坐在734大楼的楼顶吗?
Yo, you remember when we used to sit on the top of 734 building, man...
我们看着脚下的城市 谈起我们的理想
Iooking at the city, used to talk about what we gonna do?
你那时非常热衷于那些黑人的骄傲之类的东西
And you was all heavy into that black pride bullshit...
你说你要开两家日用品超市 让那些混帐东西们为你骄傲
talking like you gonna get you two grocery stores, make motherfuckers proud.
可不是嘛 你那时提着一枝AK-47出去打猎
Sure was, man, you was out hunting on a AK-47...
老是说 "我要去打仗"
talking about "I'm gonna go get warrin'."
往事不堪回首啊
Man.
就是啊
Yeah.
我们是好兄弟 B
We brothers, B.
一直都是
Always, baby.
Always.
但就有一件事 哥们儿
And just one more thing, though, man.
你知道 我不是想拿这事儿跟你挑刺
You know...I don't mean to be picky with you about this...
特别是在你为我做了这一切之后
but especially not after you did all this shit for me...
说真的 哥们儿 我被关了好久了呢 你懂我的意思吧?
look, man, I've been locked down.
可不是嘛 那就这样吧 我还要去开个会
Yeah, you know what? I got to take this meet.
你知道吗... 我回头再来找你
- You know... - I'm gonna get at you.
欢迎回来 哥们儿
Welcome home, man.
哎 是我 我落了点东西
Yo, it's me, man. I left something.
靠 果然是我的知己
Shit. My man.